redgoldfish.co.uk 2018-11-23

# Our Privacy Policy - Redgoldfish

### Privacy Policy

### We have a comprehensive privacy policy established.

We are committed to providing users of sites within our group with privacy in line with and beyond the current scope of all current legislation.

**Why Do We Operate A Privacy Policy?**

Redgoldfish Jobs is a trading brand name of Recruitive Software Ltd. Recruitive Software Ltd is committed to providing everyone who accesses one of our websites total privacy. Under the Data Protection Act 1984 and 1998 we must comply with certain regulations which are designed to ensure that any data you provide to us is processed with due care and attention.

**What Sort Of Data & Information Do We Collect?**

Recruitive Software collects personal data from Job seekers in order to help them obtain applicable job details / positions they may be looking for when visiting one of our sites. This data consists of information such as personal names, address, email address, education and employment history and the responses that are given to and or as a result of assessments administered through one of our sites, plus nationality information which we are required to collect by law.

From employers, recruitment agencies, jobs boards and other advertising clients we obtain basic data from the principle account contact and registered users under that account that are specified during the sign up process or added at a later time in order to establish the correct services to be offered and set up job posting, Job feeds, response management, multi posting and other candidate sourcing and related service facilities as required.

We also collect information in the aggregate to provide us with an understanding of the visitors and users and general demographics, profiles and candidate types visiting our websites as a whole, but which does not contain personally identifiable information.

**Why Do We Process This Personal Data?**

We have to process this personal data to help job seekers obtain the relevant job data and job matches that they may be looking for and to ensure that our advertising clients are offered the right facilities in order to ensure the highest level of return on their advertising investment. We may also use data collected in the aggregate to help us to understand our users as a company so that we may provide an ongoing and improving service to all.

**Why Do We Collect & Process Sensitive Personal Data?**

We have to collect and process sensitive Personal Data only as far as is necessary to ensure that we conform with legal requirements such as equal opportunities laws. By using one of our websites and registering details with us, users consent to us collecting and processing the personal data they have supplied and to us disclosing this information to prospective employers, recruiters, job boards and other clients in connection with the recruitment process.

**Do We Pass Data To Third Parties?**

Sometimes, where necessary, we may pass data to third parties that help us process data and to prospective or intended employers or customers for the purpose of recruitment. We may also share aggregate information with selected third parties but only as part of the recruitment process.

**How Is This Data Safeguarded?**

The security of any data supplied to us by our customers or users is of paramount importance to us. Access to personal data is only provided to our staff and third parties who help us to process the data and, in order to help with the recruitment process, to prospective employers, recruitment agencies, other jobs boards or customers.

**How Do We Let You Know If Our Policy Changes?**

Any privacy policy changes that are either due to business reasons or future changes in legislation will be posted on this page and, if substantial, may be promoted on the website or through email notification.

**What Are “Cookies” And Why Do We Use Them?**

“Cookies” are ways of saving a small amount of personal information. We use “cookies” on some of our websites to save user names and details about what type of jobs candidates are looking for or to cut down on the typing effort required for revisiting candidates where information fields are repeated. This allows easy access to our site; faster response times from our technology and assists in delivering recommendations that are relevant to you. If your computer is shared by other people, we advise that you select the “don’t remember my details” option when you sign in as a jobseeker or advertiser into an account on one of our sites. This will remove all details from the “cookie”.

**Terminology**

**Aggregate**  – this is when data is collected and processed as a total to enable us to look at such information as demographic and geographic trends, so that we can try and produce a better service for the future.

**Archiving**  – this is the process where candidate users are asked if they want their personal data to remain on the Recruitive Software database. If a user does not indicate that they wish their details to be retained, their record is deleted from the database. This means that the candidate will not be able to sign into a Recruitive Software site after deletion and also means that their details will not be accessible by any recruiters or advertising clients using one of our websites. Please note that this process is carried out in accordance with the Data Protection Act.

**Data**  – information which is being processed by equipment operating automatically in response to instructions given for that purpose is recorded with the intention that it should be processed by means of such equipment, is recorded as part of a relevant filing system or forms part of an accessible record.

**Data Protection Acts 1984 and 1998**  – these are the Acts of Parliament which set out principals relating to the use of data to ensure that the rights of the person who is the subject of the data are protected under the law.

**Personal Data**  – data which relates to a living individual who can be identified from those data, or from those data and other information which is in the possession of, or is likely to come into the possession of, Recruitive Software.

**Privacy Policy**  – this is a statement by Recruitive Software which explains the ways that we try to protect our users’ privacy.

**Recruitment Process**  – the process of gaining employment and recruiting new staff and the ongoing administrative process involved once a user has gained employment or recruited new staff.

**Recruitive Software**  – Recruitive Software Ltd and its subsidiary/associated companies and any one of our owned websites. Our cloud based technology and software products including the products branded under Job Mate, Visible Boost, Post Social, CV Mate and Job Pigeon plus others along with any of the network sites listed within Job Pigeon that are also part of our group portfolio. This also includes the sites listed under <http://www.redadvertising.co.uk/network-coverage/>

**Sensitive Personal Data**  – personal data consisting or information as to the racial or ethnic origin of the data subject, political opinions, religious beliefs or other beliefs of a similar nature, membership of a trade union, physical or mental health or condition, sexual life, the commission or alleged commission of any offence or any proceedings related to any offence.

**Third Parties**  – these are companies and people other than Recruitive Software and the group of companies of which it is part.

**Users**  – people who use our website and register their details with us for the purpose of recruitment, either to gain employment or for the purposes of recruiting new staff.
